<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: soft skills | lgsanjos' Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://lgsanjos.github.io/blog/categories/soft-skills/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lgsanjos.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-09-11T15:31:15-03:00</updated>
  <id>http://lgsanjos.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[lgsanjos]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[lgsanjos@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Win Friends and Influence People -  Dale Carnegie]]></title>
    <link href="http://lgsanjos.github.io/blog/2015/06/06/how-to-win-friends-and-influence-people/"/>
    <updated>2015-06-06T14:00:52-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://lgsanjos.github.io/blog/2015/06/06/how-to-win-friends-and-influence-people</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a best seller and a must read for people who wants to improve their soft skills, better approach and understand  people in a vast different scenarios.
Here are my notes taken by chapter.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h1>Side notes</h1>

<h3>Part1:</h3>

<h4>Fundamental techniques in handling people</h4>

<ul>
<li><p>If you want to gather honey, don&rsquo;t kick over the beehive
. Don&rsquo;t criticize people instead incentive them to do differently.
. Assume poeple their best in that situation because we never know the whole context to judge.
. &ldquo;Don&rsquo;t criticize them. They are just what we would be under similar cricumstances.&rdquo;</p></li>
<li><p>The big secret of dealing with people</p></li>
<li>Sigmund Freud said &ldquo;Everything you and I do springs from two motives: the sex urge and the desire to be great.&rdquo;

<ul>
<li>The only way to make people do something is making them wanting to do so.</li>
<li>Watch out for friends that flatters you. Flattery is telling a person precisely what he/she thinks of himself/herself.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Give sincere appreciation.</li>
<li>He who can do this has the whole wolrd with him. He who cannot walks a lonely way</li>
<li>People are interested in what they want.

<ul>
<li>The only way to influence people is to talk about what they want and how to get it.</li>
<li>if there is any secret of success it lies in the ability to get the other person&rsquo;s point of view and see thing from that person&rsquo;s angle as well as from your own.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3>Part2:</h3>

<h4>Six ways to make people like you</h4>

<ol>
<li>Do this and you&rsquo;ll be welcome anywhere</li>
<li>Dog is the only animal which does not work for living. It get&rsquo;s everthing by giving love.

<ul>
<li>The most used word is &ldquo;I&rdquo;.</li>
<li>We like people that admire us.</li>
<li>&ldquo;its the individual who is not interested in his fellow men who has the greatest diffculties in life and provides the greatest injury to others.&rdquo;</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>Poeple are deeply interest in their own world, if you care about it too they will listen and care about you.</p>

<ul>
<li>&ldquo;We are interested in others when they are interested in us&rdquo;- Publilius Syrus</li>
<li>Become genuinely interested in other people.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>A simple way to make a good first impression</p></li>
<li><p>Hapiness is always welcome anywhere.</p>

<ul>
<li>Actions speak louder than words. A smile says &ldquo;I&rsquo;m glad to see you&rdquo;.</li>
<li>Smile even when on the phone. Smiles influences your voice.</li>
<li>Never foce a smile. It&rsquo;s completely noticeable and creates a worse impression.</li>
<li>Greet and approach people with a smile and it helps people to associate you as someone who brings hapiness and wellness.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>If you don&rsquo;t do this, you are headed for trouble</p></li>
<li><p>One&rsquo;s own name is the sweetest word he/she can hear.</p>

<ul>
<li>Remember people&rsquo;s name and pronunciate/spell it correctly.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>An easy way to become a good conversationalist</p></li>
<li><p>To be a good conversationalist you must be a good listener.</p>

<ul>
<li>Remember, we like people that are interested in us. So to be an interesting pearson be interested in others.</li>
<li>You can make more friends in two months admiring others than in two years promoting yourself.</li>
<li>Encourage people to talk about themselves.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>How to interest people</p></li>
<li><p>The royal road to a person&rsquo;s heart is to talk about things he/she treasures most.</p>

<ul>
<li>Try to find what interest people and talk about it, people will be interested in you.</li>
<li>Talk in terms of the others person&rsquo;s interest.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>How to make people like you instantly</p></li>
<li>Remember that everyone want feel important.

<ul>
<li>You don&rsquo;t have to take credit for decisions.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>


<h3>Part 3:</h3>

<h4>How to win people to your way of thinking</h4>

<ol>
<li>You can&rsquo;t win an argument</li>
<li><p>The best way to approach an argument is to avoid the argument.</p>

<ul>
<li>If you proven someone is wrong it will hurt their pride and feeling of importance, it&rsquo;s not constructive.</li>
<li>A conflict is never ended by an argument but by tact and diplomacy.</li>
<li>When someone argues and bring some different point of view, recognizes and show appreciation to minimize the stress.</li>
<li>When people yell at each other, it&rsquo;s not communication it&rsquo;s just noise.</li>
<li>Look for areas of agreement.</li>
<li>Divergent ideas usually means different points of view, try to understand the other&rsquo;s point of view not to prove you are right.</li>
<li>When you disagree and an argument seems near, listen first. Do try to understand deeply what the other is saying instead of judge as wrong.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>A sure way of making enemies - And how to avoid it</p></li>
<li>A sure way of making enemies is telling they are wrong, know nothing. It deeply hurts the feeling of importance and self pride.

<ul>
<li>Even when sure of what you are going to say, offer the idea as a suggestion never pushes it. When an idea is pushed it means &ldquo;I&rsquo;m better than you&rdquo;.</li>
<li>Respect other&rsquo;s opinions and treat them courteously.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>Always use diplomacy.</p></li>
<li><p>If you are wrong, admit it</p></li>
<li>Admit it quickly and emphatically</li>
<li><p>Be humble and people will have a forgiving attitude towards you.</p></li>
<li><p>A drop of honey</p></li>
<li><p>“So with men, if you would win a man to your cause, first convince him that you are his sincere friend”</p>

<ul>
<li>Start negotiation in a friendly way and it will influence on the other&rsquo;s judgment.</li>
<li>We like to help friends and people who care about us, it&rsquo;s clever to be friendly with people so in need a help is more likely to come.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>The secret of socrates</p></li>
<li><p>When starting a conversation, talk about in common points not on divergences. Emphasizes what you have in common.</p>

<ul>
<li>This feeling of being right is very powerful and should take place before the divergences.</li>
<li>Try to keep your opponent saying &ldquo;yes, yes&hellip; yes&rdquo; instead of &ldquo;no&rdquo;. Once a &ldquo;no&rdquo; takes place, a pearson will try to remain consistent with that for sake of pride.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>The safety valve in handling complaints</p></li>
<li><p>When complaining people have a stream of thoughts that wants to talk about. Never interrupt them, listen everything first, wait the other&rsquo;s person finishes first.</p>

<ul>
<li>Encourage them to express themselves.</li>
<li>Let the other person do a great deal of the talking.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>How to get cooperation</p></li>
<li><p>People like to buy but not to be sold. Most people prefer to feel that they are actiong on their own ideas not on what were sold to them.</p>

<ul>
<li>Let the others take credits for ideas.</li>
<li>Ask for theirs ideas or advice about something.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>A formula that will work wonders for you</p></li>
<li><p>Do not condemn someone for being wrong.</p>

<ul>
<li>Put yourself in other&rsquo;s shoes and try to figure out why they act how they do or why they would say something like they did.</li>
<li>If there is any secret of success it lies on see through someone&rsquo;s point of view as clear as ours point.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>What everybody wants</p></li>
<li><p>Three-fourths of the people you meet want sympathy. Give it to them and they will love you.</p>

<ul>
<li>Before you speak back to someone who has offended you or is debating you, remember to try and react differently than just anyone would. Respond how a wise person would react, not just any fool.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>An appeal that everybody likes</p></li>
<li><ol type="a">
<li>Pierpont Morgan said: &ldquo;Rverybody usually has two reasons for doing anything: one that sounds good, and then their real reason.&rdquo;.</li>
<li>Use noble motives that impacts other people. Like mother&rsquo;s love, children education, environment or any noble cause that people share.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><p>The movies do it. Tv Does it. Why don&rsquo;t you do it?</p></li>
<li><p>Drama. Dramatize your ideas it turns out to be more interesting and get more attention.</p></li>
<li><p>When nothing else works, try this</p></li>
<li>People love the chance to express themselves, their worth, and to show their importance. So listen to them.

<ul>
<li>Keep the door open to people approach you.</li>
<li>Stimulate competition so people will try to outreach to prove themselves. It&rsquo;s better than pointing fingers with no constructive meaning.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>


<h3>Part 4:</h3>

<h4>Be a leader: How to change people without giving offense or arousing resentment</h4>

<ol>
<li>If you must find fault, this is the way to begin</li>
<li><p>Praise before the bad news.</p>

<ul>
<li>If you are firing someone tell he/she the bright side first and sinceres praise before firing itself. It avoid the feeloing that the decision were personal.</li>
<li>Imagine a dentist about to perform drilling. Yes, the patient is about to get drilled, but the dentist gives him Novacain to dull the pain.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>How to criticize - and not be hated for it</p></li>
<li><p>It&rsquo;s common to start with a sincere praise followed by a &ldquo;but&rdquo;. When heard this poeple might doubt about the praises. It&rsquo;s better to use the word &ldquo;and&rdquo; and continue with no direct criticism instead encourage to the right way</p>

<ul>
<li>The praise now comes off as sincere and may make that person want to live up to our expectations.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>Talk about you own mistakes first</p></li>
<li><p>It feels a lot better to hear someone talk about their faults and kind of “get down on your level” in a sense before they point out yours.</p>

<ul>
<li>Admiting your failures is a humble act. Poeple will feel safe to share theirs as well.</li>
<li>Also it encourages people to analyze their failures and change their behavior.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>No one likes to take orders</p></li>
<li>Giving suggestions instead of giving orders is much more effective and seve person&rsquo;s pride.

<ul>
<li>Asking questions instead of ordering make people to feel they are participating in the decisions and are effective.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
